<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Urbanism.guide – Transportation</title><link>https://example.org/austin/transportation/</link><description>Recent content in Transportation on Urbanism.guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://example.org/austin/transportation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Austin: Project Connect</title><link>https://example.org/austin/transportation/project_connect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/austin/transportation/project_connect/</guid><description>
&lt;p>TODO&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Austin: TxDOT and CAMPO</title><link>https://example.org/austin/transportation/txdot_and_campo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/austin/transportation/txdot_and_campo/</guid><description>
&lt;p>TxDOT and CAMPO are two related but independent organizations. TxDOT plans and builds road projects. While CAMPO is the non-representative governing body that reviews and approves their plans.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="txdot">TxDOT&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Texas Department of Transportation is the state&amp;rsquo;s department that plans and implements roads for cars and trucks on ROWs that they own or have access to use. In principal TxDOT &lt;em>should&lt;/em> create transportation options for all modes of transportation. However in practice and &lt;a href="">in law&lt;/a> they spend almost all of their funding on road expansions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TxDOT road expansions include highways as well as many regular streets within cities and towns that they also own. This means that in some cases urbanist efforts to improve certain roads are frustrated by the state&amp;rsquo;s desire to harm its people over petty grievances. Due to this fatal crashes on state owned roadways continue to rise, while on non-state roads fatalities have remained flat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://example.org/media/txdot_fatalities_increasing.png" alt="Chart showing a significant increase in fatalities on State owned roads over time">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="funding">Funding&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://statutes.capitol.texas.gov/Docs/CN/htm/CN.3/CN.3.49-g.v2.htm">Proposition 1&lt;/a>: Directs 37.5% of existing oil and natural gas production taxes (aka severance) to TxDOT so that &amp;ldquo;the funds may only be used for constructing, maintaining, and acquiring rights-of-way for public roadways other than toll roads.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://statutes.capitol.texas.gov/Docs/CN/htm/CN.8/CN.8.7-c.htm">Proposition 7&lt;/a>: Directs portions of state sales and use taxes, as well as motor vehicle sale and rental taxes to: &amp;ldquo;(1) construct, maintain, or acquire rights of way for public roadways other than toll roads; or (2) repay the principal of and interest on general obligation bonds issued as authorized by Section 49-p, Article III, of this constitution.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In combination these propositions have lead to tens of billions of state tax dollars being directed towards maintaining and expanding highways and all the negativies that car dependent infrastructure brings to us and our cities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TODO: Explain where this money was taken away from&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="campo">CAMPO&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Capital Area Metropolitan Planning Organization is a 22-member board that makes transportation policy decisions. This board contains 4 members from Austin which means that Austin&amp;rsquo;s overall voting and decision making power is significantly lower than its population. This sometimes leads to poor decision making that negatively impacts Austin because our needs are not adequately represented.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="funding-1">Funding&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>TODO&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Austin: Vision Zero</title><link>https://example.org/austin/transportation/vision_zero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/austin/transportation/vision_zero/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Vision zero is a multifaceted strategy that is being used across the world to reduce traffic related injuries and fatalities down to zero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At a broad level vision zero incorporates:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Safer street design&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Evidence-based policy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Public engagement&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Targeted law enforcement&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>While Vision Zero is primarily policy and research much of what is actually implemented is done via the &lt;a href="https://www.austintexas.gov/department/austin-strategic-mobility-plan">Austin Strategic Mobility Plan&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="austin-strategic-mobility-plan">Austin Strategic Mobility Plan&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>TODO&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="transportation-safety-program">Transportation Safety Program&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>TODO
Link: &lt;a href="https://data.austintexas.gov/stories/s/Transportation-Safety-Projects/smw6-wzhe/">https://data.austintexas.gov/stories/s/Transportation-Safety-Projects/smw6-wzhe/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>